SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Summary

Total 6.3 years of strong SAP ABAP and HR-ABAP development experience in HR, Payroll SD and other SAP modules. Extensively worked on Interactive Reports, ALV and dialog programming. Extensively worked on HR/Payroll Logical Database (LDB) reports. Good experience in ABAP/4 interfaces development, Data conversions, Enhancements, User Exits and BAPI. Multiple projects on Data Migration with BDCs, Legacy System Migration workbench (LSMW) for data upload for various SAP projects. Experience in using various modularization techniques like subroutines, Function Modules, RFC's and class modules. Experience in creation, modification and maintenances of HR actions, Info types and Payroll wage types data. Good experience in Dialog programming, designing and developing layouts and forms using SMARTFORMS SAP scripts. Experience of performance analysis and tuning using various debugging tools like run time analysis and SQL trace. SAP Functional knowledge and Experience of HR modules, Payroll and Time Management. Excellent Trouble shooting and debugging skills. Good experience using ABAP workbench tools. Reporting, customization, conversion and data extraction. Excellent Trouble shooting and debugging skills. Excellent communication and time management skill with strong analytical, problem solving and decision making capability. Good understanding of both business processes and technical development. Provided multiple training to team member for HR-ABAP, LSMW and BDC programming Knowledge in ASP.net, JavaScript. I have 8 months experience as a Project officer with Science NGO other than SAP. Highlights

SAP R/3 6.0 ECC. ABAP Reports, ALV reports, LSMW, BDC, BADI, BAPI, User Exits, Info types, LDB reports. Languages: ABAP, C and C++. HTML, ASP.net

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Surveymonkey i1/4 Seattle

- Total 2.3 years [04th January, 2010 to 12th April, 2012] Received four performance monitory award by the supervisor, Promoted to senior role within a year of joining the company.
- Leading IT outsourcing and consulting company across globe.
- Roles and Responsibilities Single point of contact for all HR ABAP development, modification, corrections and queries of SAP HR and Payroll modules.
- Key resource for ABAP development for any SAP module.
- Single point of contact for ABAP code and documentation review of any request.
- Responsible to attend meetings, generate call logs and status updates.
- Knowledge sharing for HR ABAP programming skill and SAP HR Modules.
- All reported issues were resolved and reported successfully, nearly more than 100 for upgrade and support project.
- Received performance monitory award such as 'Organizes quality work efforts!' Interviewed candidate for required skillset of the project, primarily for SAP HR ABAP programming.
- Major Development and contributions Design, documented and implemented successfully new SD process module project as per the client requirement single handed.
- The project module had multiple test and update process with many BDC programming and different type of ALV report structure.
- During upgrade of SAP ECC 5.0 to ECC 6.0 successfully recovered all the affected standard and implemented report manually as and when required.
- Checked and meet the SAP note requirements.
- Documented and reported as well.
- Solved HR Adobe form issues and implemented dynamic code for Bank detail printing.
- Programmed new conditions to meet requirement of client payroll team.
- Support team extensively for another project.
- Trace out all the possible code errors and make sure every single of them is corrected and documented properly.
- Code implemented from my part was review with zero defect and resulted successfully.
- Received performance monitory award as well.
- Extensively involved in implementation of Bascule project and SAP Upgrade project.

Software Engineer

Hulu i1/4 Seattle

- 6 Months [04th January, 2010 to 09th July, 2010] Offered permanent role with 'Accenture' within 6 months of association.
- Leading IT solution provider consulting company in USA and India.
- Roles and Responsibility:.
- Performed under all the standard and commitment level with the contractual company.
- Delivered, documented and implemented successfully all assigned task within time.

Officer IT

Interxion i1/4 Amsterdam

- Total 3.6 years [01th July, 2006 to 09th Dec, 2009] 6 months work for Bachelor degree project [01th Jan, 2006 to 30th Jun, 2006] After completing bachelor degree project offer full time employment, Once congratulate by HR president for delivering MIS report.
- $\bullet \;\;$ Leading top 10 pharmaceutical company in India having international presence.
- Roles and Responsibility: Single point of contact for all SAP HR ABAP development.
- Primary contact for SAP HR, OM, PA and PD modules functional guires.
- Secondary contact for SAP Payroll functional quires.

- One of the main resource of ABAP team.
- Remain key resource for SAP implementation and support team.
- Single point of contact for 'Zydus Employee Management Portal (ZEMS)' for any query, maintenance, development and user support.
- Part of implementation of ESS portal.
- Provide support, training to new IT hired programmer or project trainee.
- Major Development and Contributions More than 35 new SAP HR ABAP design, documented and implemented successfully.
- Design, documented and implemented all BAPIs required to be implemented for ESS portal.
- Single point of contact for any new request for SAP HR ABAP development.
- Extensively worked on LSMW, BDC, Functional Modules, and Standard Text, ABAP ALV reports using LDB, User Exits, Info Types and SAP Script.
- Successfully implemented new Info Types, actions and LDB reports.
- Designed, developed and successfully implemented critical modules/reports such as MIS report, Full and final statement process, Cost Statement, Loan Report, Payroll status check, PF statement print, Employees' investment declaration print format.
- Extended on call support provided to end users to understand SAP functionalities.
- Provided multiple training to understand HR-ABAP programming, BDC and LSMW processes.
- Provided extended support to implement ABAP development for other SAP modules to meet deadlines.
- Provide extended support for maintaining the status log/report status, presentations to the team lead.
- Non-IT Experience Science Education NGO: VASCSC [Vikram A Sarabhai Community Science Center] www.vascsc.org Role:
 Temporary Term for Science Project.

Project Officer

City

- 8 Months [8th May, 2012 to 31st Dec, 2012] Established science NGO and highly active about educational awareness, educational training programs.
- Brief about the project: On wheel (Dedicated Science Train) Science expedition to spread awareness about Biodiversity of India, basic understanding of Science subject such as Mathematics, Physics, and Chemistry through models and experiments.
- Roles and Responsibility: Prepared Anthology for Biodiversity subject contains information about Indian Biodiversity and the total 13 coaches' info.
- Coordinated Science Educators Training for Science Express Travelled with the Train on and off nearly for 3 months at many locations and help main coordinator to manage the Science Educator team, and report accordingly.
- Prepared and submitted reports and on-going daily activity at the different location.
- Extended my knowledge and support to Lab activity explaining Physic experiments to students and basic Biodiversity knowledge at respective location platform.
- Prepare Data for different media news for each and every location, using the data design multiple comparison charts and a complete brief Media report to submit the project authorities.

Education

Bachelor : Information Technology Engineering , June, 2006 IT Information Technology Engineering L.D College of Engineering $i\frac{1}{4}$ City , India

Skills

ASP.net, ABAP, Adobe, basic, C, C++, charts, Chemistry, consulting, client, Dec, documentation, Educator, ERP, experiments, Functional, HTML, HR, team lead, Employee Management, Mathematics, meetings, ESS, MIS, Payroll, Physics, presentations, processes, programmer, programming, quality, Express, requirement, SAP, SAP R/3 6.0, SAP HR, SD, Script, supervisor, user support, training programs, type, Upgrade